<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stars &amp; Sea</title>
    <link>https://zhangyuqing.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Stars &amp; Sea</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://zhangyuqing.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://zhangyuqing.github.io/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhangyuqing.github.io/home/</guid>
      <description>This is Yuqing’s homepage.
Education  Boston University (Boston, MA; Sep. 2015 – present) Ph.D. Candidate in Bioinformatics (Jointly advised by W. Evan Johnson &amp;amp; Giovanni Parmigiani) Boston University (Boston, MA; Sep. 2015 – Sep. 2017) M.S. in Bioinformatics Peking University (Beijing, China; Sep. 2011 – July 2015) B.S. in Applied Mathematics (Probability and Statistics) Minor in Psychology   Experience  Takeda Data Science Institute, Takeda Pharmaceuticals (Cambridge, MA; June 2017 – Aug.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://zhangyuqing.github.io/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhangyuqing.github.io/projects/</guid>
      <description>Completed Lung cancer classification from CT scan images using deep CNNs 2017 Data Science Bowl Kaggle Competition
 Implemented U-Net with Python and Tensorflow according to literature for nodule segmentation Developed deep convolutional neural networks for lung cancer classification Applied batch normalization, drop-out layers, and tuned parameters to improve prediction accuracy Augmented training data by random cropping and merging the training set with images from public databases of CT scans Achieved performance comparable to top-50 out of nearly 2000 participating teams   A multivariate Gaussian Network model for detection of multiple perturbations in gene regulartory networks  Reference-batch ComBat: a linear model with empirical Bayes shrinkage for batch correction Batch effect refers to non-biological variations in gene expression of samples generated under different conditions in microarray experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://zhangyuqing.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhangyuqing.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Journal Papers 2018  Zhang, Y., Bernau, C., Parmigiani, G., &amp;amp; Waldron, L. (2018). The impact of different sources of heterogeneity on loss of accuracy from genomic prediction models. Biostatistics (Oxford, England) Zhang, Y., Jenkins, D. F., Manimaran, S., &amp;amp; Johnson, W. E. (2018). Alternative empirical Bayes models for adjusting for batch effects in genomic studies. BMC bioinformatics, 19(1), 262 Griffin, P. J., Zhang, Y., Johnson, W. E., &amp;amp; Kolaczyk, E.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software</title>
      <link>https://zhangyuqing.github.io/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhangyuqing.github.io/software/</guid>
      <description>R/Bioconductor packages simulatorZ Zhang Y, Bernau C, Waldron L (2018). simulatorZ: Simulator for Collections of Independent Genomic Data Sets. R package version 1.16.0. https://bioconductor.org/packages/release/bioc/html/simulatorZ.html
 reference-batch ComBat Leek JT, Johnson WE, Parker HS, Fertig EJ, Jaffe AE, Storey JD, Zhang Y, Torres LC (2019). sva: Surrogate Variable Analysis. R package version 3.30.1. https://bioconductor.org/packages/release/bioc/html/sva.html
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DESCEND - Gene expression distribution deconvolution in scRNA-seq</title>
      <link>https://zhangyuqing.github.io/2018/10/descend/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zhangyuqing.github.io/2018/10/descend/</guid>
      <description>Microarray and bulk RNA-seq data measure.
Background knowledge  Goal of this paper  Methods behind DESCEND  Results Model evaluation  Case studies Effect of cell size on differential non-zero mean and fraction analysis  DESCEND improves accuracy of cell type identification, by selecting better highly variable genes      Take-home messages  When all across-cell differences are accounted for, Poisson distribution is sufficient to capture technical noise in UMI-based scRNA-seq counts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>